卡尔:我妻子总是揪住这个不放手,她说:'卡尔,
Carl: So in front of all my in-laws, my wife spins around;
想想办法证明你是心理学家,
she says to me Carl,
花点功夫,掏点钱先把你自己的问题解决了.
prove you're a psychiatrist worth a hundred bucks an hour by healing yourself.
杰森:她居然这么对你,那你怎么回敬的呢?
Jason: So what do you feel like saying when she does that to you?
卡尔:我怎么回敬的?
Carl: What do I feel like saying?
杰森:嗯哼?
Jason: Uh huh.
卡尔:我会告诉你的.
Carl: I'll tell you
卡尔:嗯,现在好多了.
Carl: I feel better.
杰森:耶!
Jason: Yeah.
卡尔:感觉好多了.
Carl: I feel good.
杰森:呃哈.
Jason: Uh huh.
杰森:时间到了.
Jason: Well, time's up.
卡尔:谢谢你医生.
Carl: Thank you doctor.
杰森:不对,应该谢谢你医生.
Jason: No, thank you doctor.
杰森:现在该我了.
Jason: Alright, my turn.
卡尔:让我想想,上星期你说过你感觉很压抑.
Carl: So let's see last week you said you were feeling depressed.
杰森:是有这话.不过,现在我已经全好了.
Jason: Yeah, well now I'm terrific.
卡尔:噢!那好,不过你还得付给我一百美元诊费,谢谢光临.
Carl: Oh, good.That'll be a hundred bucks, thank you for coming in.
杰森:卡尔,我认为你是在开玩笑,
Jason: Carl, I think the reason that you're joking is because you feel
因为你让你的同事感到很不自在.
uncomfortable dealing with a colleague.
卡尔:其实我一直都想对自己这么说.
Carl: I always wanted to say that to a Carl.
卡尔:你曾声称你感觉极其的不爽.
Carl: So, you uh, you claim you're terrific.
杰森:声称?卡尔,
Jason: Claim?Carl, if that's going to be your attitude,
如果你这样说,我就不告诉你了.
I may not even tell you.
卡尔:杰森.
Carl: Jason.
杰森:成!成!别吓唬我了.我说.
Jason: Alright, alright, stop brow-beating me, I'll talk.
杰森:我过了一个很不错的一周.这一周里我的自我感觉确实不错,
Jason: I'll talk.I have had such a week, I've had an incredible week.
不仅自我怀疑消失了,而且一切都恢复了正常,
Not only is my self-doubt gone, but I've got a second wind.
也许这是我一生中,最有意思的一段时间.
I, I've uh, this may be the most incredible week of my life.
这些年来,我从来没有感觉到像这样富有活力.
I just haven't felt this positive, this energized, this essential in years.
卡尔:请你发个音听听.
Carl: Well try a little vocalization.
Jason: Vocalization, okay Whoa, wow, whippee, whippee, whew, yeah
卡尔:是WO,WO,VP,VP?
Carl: Is that whoa, whoa, whippee, whew?
Jason: No, that was one whoa, and two whippees, and a whew, like that so
就这些,你可别搞错了,卡尔.
get with it Carl.
杰森:我是说,
Jason: I mean, just to think that it was one week ago and I'm,
就在一周以前我还处在……
I'm staring right into the...
卡尔:自我怀疑的深渊.
Carl: Abyss of self doubt.
杰森:哇噢!你是不是在认真听我说话.
Jason: Wow, you do pay attention.
卡尔:我当然在听了.
Carl: Of course I pay attention.
杰森:很好,请你为我想一想,
Jason: To think that I was,
我一直希望有人能够帮助我解答一些疑难,卡尔,
I was looking for someone to answer my questions Carl,
尽管我一直在替别人解答难题,
and what I really needed all the time was for me to help someone else
就这么简单,这么实际.
with theirs.It was so simple, so basic.
卡尔:你以为我没在听你说?
Carl: You didn't think I was listening to you, did you?
杰森:最理想的地方是在办公室,
Jason: I have the perfect place to start.
和我的病人在一起.那是上星期三,
Alright, it all began in my office, with a patient.It was last Wednesday.
我和那个病人……
I'm sitting in my office.
卡尔:等等,你连星期三也在办公.
Carl: Wait a minute, you have office hours on Wednesday?
杰森:闭嘴,卡尔.
Jason: Shut up Carl.
杰森:好了,罗赞,今天就到这,下星期老时间.西维尔大夫,我有话要对你说,在离开之前,我一定要说.
Jason: Alright Rosanne, that's our session for this week.Same time next week?
罗赞:西维尔大夫,我有点事要和你说,
Rosanne: Dr.Seaver, I have something to say to you,
在我离开这之前.
and I must say it before I leave.
杰森:好吧,请吧.
Jason: Okay, sure.
罗赞:我说不出口.
Rosanne: I can't say it.
杰森:那就下星期再说.
Jason: Alright then, we'll talk next week.
罗赞:不,这可不行.
Rosanne: No we won't.
杰森:为什么?
Jason: Pardon me?
罗赞:我想另外找一位大夫治病.
Rosanne: I'm gonna start seeing another therapist.
杰森:什么?
Jason: What?
罗赞:你不会生我的气吧.
Rosanne: You aren't mad at me, are you?
杰森:不,但我想我们应该……
Jason: No, no, but I think we should discuss
罗赞:我怕把这个消息告诉你,你会伤心,
Rosanne: Oh I was so afraid I was gonna tell you,
你会在地上打滚.
and you were gonna start crying, and rolling around on the floor.
杰森:不不,绝不会有这种事的,罗赞.可我们得探讨.
Jason: No, no, I hardly ever do that anymore, Rosanne.
杰森:你真是个好人,你想的比任何人都细心.
Jason: But I think we should
罗赞:倒没什么,只是你为什么要另找大夫?
Rosanne: It is so nice of you to be so nice about this.
杰森:为什么?我认为这对你我很重要.
Jason: No problem, it's just, why do you want to see another therapist?
罗赞:为什么?
Rosanne: Why?
杰森:这对你我都很重要
Jason: I think this is important for you and me.
罗赞:何解?
Rosanne: Why?
杰森:是呀,为什么?
Jason: Yes why?
罗赞:为什么?
Rosanne: Why?
罗赞:因为我的病你根本治不了.
Rosanne: Because you're not helping me at all.
杰森:明白了.
Jason: I see.
罗赞:不过这并不是你的过错,西维尔医生,
Rosanne: Well, it's really not your fault, Dr.Seaver.
你已经尽了你的义务了,
You've done everything humanly possible.
我过去究竟犯过一些什么毛病,
How could you know that my problem stems from events in one of my previous
这个问题对你来说,你是无法知道的.
lives on Earth.
杰森:罗赞,你又看过了.
Jason: Rosanne, have you been watching Oprah again?
罗赞:那是部好片子.
Rosanne: It's a very good show.
杰森:是的,你应该按你想的去做.
Jason: Yes, well, ah ah, you should do whatever you think is best.
罗赞:真不想伤你感情,你只不过没能成功.
Rosanne: Well I just didn't wanna hurt your feelings.Just because you failed.
杰森:别胡说了,不不,
Jason: That's nonsense.No, no, no, I uh,
我只想告诉你,
I just want you to know that if you don't find the answer in some previous
如果你找不到上世纪的答案,我办公室的大门永远向你敞开着.
century, my door's always open to you.
罗赞:谢谢.
Rosanne: Thank you.
杰森:!布瑞格太太刚巧证实了我最近的情绪,
Jason: Oprah!Mrs.Flagg just confirmed how I'd been feeling lately.
最新资料,布瑞格完全停止了心理治疗,
File update: Rosanne Flagg is terminating her session because she's a
因为她完全是疯了,不,
totally loon.No, she's terminating because I have failed her Inactive
她终止治疗完全是我的失败,撤销,就像我,
Just like me.It started me wondering, I mean,
她提醒了我,我是说我能够拿出什么证据来说明,
what proof did I have that any of my patients were truly better off for
我的病人是真的康复了呢,我能胜任吗?
having seen me?Was I competent?
杰森:本,过半小时才开饭呢.
Jason: Ben, dinner's in half an hour!
本:我已经等不及了.
Ben: I'm looking forward to it.
杰森:好了,别这样,别这样,我在烧饭呢.
Jason: Stop, no, no, c'mon, I'm cooking tonight.
本:又是烤豆?
Ben: Baked beans?
杰森:对,不好吗?
Jason: Sure, why not?
本:太好了.
Ben: Alright!
杰森:在厨房我还能露一手,再也不去研究什么心理学了,
Jason: At least I'm still useful in the kitchen.
反正我还有很多事情可以做,消防队员,宇航员,
I should never have gone into psychiatry lots of things I could have done.
牛仔,厨师.
Even a fireman, or an astronaut cowboy.Chef.
麦琪:嗨,亲爱的.
Maggie: Hi honey!
杰森:在在在.
Jason: Yeah, yeah, yeah,
杰森:你在干一件最艰巨的事情时,
Jason's voiceover: One of the toughest parts about what we do is that
千万别对你妻子提起它,有时Maggie干的最漂亮的事,
you can't talk to your wife about your work,
就是离你远远的.
and sometimes the smartest thing Maggie can do is just stay away from me.
麦琪:我什么时候干过最漂亮的事情,而又离你远远的了?
Maggie: once told me the smartest thing I can do is stay away from you.
杰森:我要是你我就走.
Jason: If I were you I'd move.
杰森:她走了,可女儿和她的朋友们又来了.
Jason's voiceover: She did.Then my daughter and her friends arrived.
开萝尔:嗨,爸爸.
Carol: Hi dad.
杰森:嗨.
Jason: Yeah.
开萝尔:爸爸,我们要查阅很多大学手册,
Carol: Dad, we've got a ton of college brochures to go through,
德比和薛丽能在这用晚餐吗?
so is it okay if Deb and Shel stay for dinner?
杰森:她们没有自己的家吗?
Jason: What, they don't have homes of their own?
开萝尔:爸爸.
Carol: Dad!
杰森:不可我是好心的卡斯比.
Jason: I'm sorry, I'm not Bill Cosby.
黛比:算了,开萝尔,我爸爸也这么古怪.
Deb: It's okay Carol, my father's weird too.
雪莉:别提吃完饭的事了,我今晚减肥,
Shel: Forget about dinner Mr.Seaver.
不能进食.
I'm on this super-strict diet, I can't have real food.
黛比:我也在减肥.
Deb: I'm on that same diet!
开萝尔:为什么不来点馅饼呢?
Carol: Well why don't we just order out for pizza.
黛比:好啊.
Deb: Great!
雪莉:好!
Shel: Great!
开萝尔:好
Carol: Okay!
谢丽尔:德比,有家医科学校,在海滨,就在海滩边上.
Cheryl: Debbie, here's a medical school in Haiti, right on the beach!
黛比:喔!哇噢!
Deb: Oh wow!
开萝尔:你就不想进真正的医科大学.
Carol: Don't, don't you want to go to a real medical school?
黛比:你瞧这里的风景.
Deb: Wow, look at these cabanas!
开萝尔:爸爸你说说,医科大学该是什么样的?
Carol: Dad, tell Debbie where you went to medical school.
黛比:你也进过医科大学?
Deb: You went to medical school?!?
开萝尔:当然了!
Carol: Well of course he did.
黛比:对不起,我还以为你只是个江湖郎中呢.
Deb: Oh wow, I'm sorry, I thought you were just a psychiatrist.
杰森:我只是个江湖郎中?
Jason's voiceover: I felt like just a psychiatrist.
雪莉:他是说你胆量,素质都差点.
Shel: She means you don't, like, look at guts and stuff.
开萝尔:对精神病人,我父亲有胆量,说呀爸爸.
Carol: My father deals with mental guts.Tell em dad.
杰森:对精神病人,我有胆量.
Jason: I deal with mental guts.
迈克:让一让,让一让,不然要流血的,嗨,
Mike: Alright, let the man through, move it or bleed.Hey dad.
爸爸,好了Boner,把东西就放在这吧.
Alright Bone, just put her down, right there.
开萝尔:什么?爸爸.
Carol: What!Dad!
迈克:爸爸,你听我说,
Mike: Hey Dad, I'm not screwing around here.
这是艺术课的作品,是回家作业.
This is a uh project for art classit's real homework.
开萝尔:是我们先来这的.
Carol: We were here first.
波纳:迈克,别着急.
Boner: Mikey, please.
迈克:快点.
Mike: In a minute, Bone.
开萝尔:你放到别处去吧.
Carol: Well go somewhere else, Mike.
迈克:爸爸,
Mike: Dad, alright, look, it's up to you,
跟你说话呢,要不你就放我好好做家庭作业,
either you say she start letting me do my homework, or uh,
要么就听Carol喳喳叫.
you gotta listen to Carol's whining.
开萝尔:【大声抱怨】
Carol: [Cries out in annoyance]
波纳:我撑不住了,我撑不住了.
Boner: I'm gonna drop it, I'm gonna drop it.
杰森:你们俩都给我住嘴.
Jason: Hold on, will you two stop arguing.
迈克:这下你高兴了.
Mike: Oh there, are you happy now?
杰森:你要为你的行为做出解释.
Jason: You better have a real good reason for all this.
迈克:我们想把波纳的造型作为艺术课的作业.
Mike: Oh heck yeah dad.We're doing a torso study of Boner for art class.
波纳:Mike要我拿出各种东西,
Boner: Yeah, that's why Mikey said I should carry in everything:
为了考察我的造型.
uh to pump up my physique.
迈克:爸爸,这是吉尔,
Mike: Oh uh Dad, this is Jill.
她付的石膏钱,
She uh, she paid for all this plaster, so if you're gonna kick us out,
如果你想赶我们走,得先问问她.
you're gonna have to answer to her.
杰森:嗨,你瞧我们在……
Jason: Hi, look uh, take this
吉尔:是要赶我们走.
Jill: So are we kicked out or what?
杰森:地下室不错.
Jason: The basement's fine.
Mike: Oh yeah, yeah, the basement, that should work.Come on Bone.Let's go
波纳:还有三袋石膏谁去拿.
Boner: So who's gonna get the other three bags of plaster?
迈克:猜猜吧.
Mike: Guess.
开萝尔:你们刚才看见谁了?
Carol: Did you see who that was?
雪莉:你能信吗?
Shel: Could you believe it?
黛比:她在你家里,开萝尔.
Deb: She's in your home, Carol.
杰森:你们是在说……
Jason: So what's the matter with uh...
开萝尔:吉尔?
Carol: Jill?
开萝尔:对.
Jason: Yeah.
迈克:很好,真是太好了,
Mike: Oh nice, nice, very nice ladies.
小姐们,爸爸,他们告吉尔的状,
Dad, whatever they said about Jill is a lie.
都是捏造的,她从不惹人.
That teacher deserved to be slugged.
杰森:这姑娘过去怎么样?
Jason: So what's the story with that girl?
开萝尔:过去她除了说下流话从来不开口,
Carol: Well, she never talks to anyone except to be nasty,
她总是惹是生非的.
and she's always getting in trouble, Dad.
她在校长办公室呆的时候,远远超过了迈克,
I mean, she spends more time in the principal's office than Mike,
更糟的是……
and worse she...
雪莉:她从来不注意修饰,也不注意整洁.
Shel: She's not into clothes, or makeup, or anything that's important.
杰森:这没关系.
Jason: Never mind.
开萝尔:雪莉,这都无关紧要,
Carol: Shelly, that doesn't matter.
我要说的是,她实际上已经要退学了.
What I was gonna say is that she's practically flunking out.
黛比:是呀,我也正想退学呢.
Deb: So, I'm practically flunking out too.
杰森:你是谁?
Jason: Do I know you?
本:快,举起手来.
Ben: Die alien maggot!
本:你已经被抓住了,再跑我就打死你.
Ben: Gothar sword.Gothar sword.
杰森:看来没有比我更不幸的人了.
Jason: Let's see if there's anyone in here worse off than me.Obituaries.
吉尔:你是心理医生?
Jill: So, you're a head-shrinker.
杰森:要我帮点什么?
Jason: Uh-huh.Something I can do for you?
吉尔:诶.
Jill: Umm.
众女孩:呃-呃!波纳!
Girls: Eww, Boner!
迈克:天呐,
Mike: Boy, I swear,
我真该死,我要不求波纳帮忙就好了,
when am I ever gonna learn not to ask Boner to help me,
我已经痛苦多少遍了.
I mean how many times do I have to get burned?
波纳:我已经说过对不起了.
Boner: I said I was sorry.
迈克:别担心爸爸,厨房会像新的一样.
Mike: Don't worry Dad, the kitchen will be as good as new.
杰森:迈克,我不是说过去地下室的吗?
Jason: Mike, you guys said you'd work in the basement.
迈克:别怪我,爸爸,
Mike: Hey don't blame me dad,
是波纳把整袋的石膏都洒在地上了.
Boner's the one who dropped the whole bag of plaster on the floor.
波纳:是啊,要是有人帮忙就不会这样了.
Boner: Oh yeah, well I wouldn't have dropped it if I hadda had some help.
吉尔:你还要人帮忙?
Jill: You're beyond help.
迈克:吉尔进来.
Mike: Eh, come on Jill.
吉尔:就来.很高兴跟你交谈.
Jill: Coming...Nice talkin' to you.
杰森:恩?
Jason: Huh?
开萝尔:他们不会来打扰我们了.
Carol: Arg, they won't bother us in here.Hi dad!
杰森:恩.
Jason: Mm hmm.
开萝尔:嘿,爸爸.
Carol: Uh, dad?
杰森:嗯?
Jason: Uh huh?
开萝尔:爸爸,你还想呆在这?
Carol: Are you planning on staying here?
杰森:是我碍事吗?
Jason: Am I in your way?
开萝尔:不不不,要是你想在这,
Carol: Oh no, no, no, I mean but if you're gonna stay here,
那我们换个地方.
we'll go somewhere else.
杰森:不不不,你们呆着,
Jason: No, no, no, no, you stay.No, I'll uh, I'll go somewhere else.
我另外再找个地方,我去哪都行,只要你们能够快活就可以了.
It doesn't matter where I go.It's not like I'm doing anything useful, right?
开萝尔:谢谢爸爸.
Carol: Thanks dad.
杰森:见鬼.
Jason: Geez.
吉尔:没想到心理医生会这样.
Jill: I didn't know shrinks kicked stuff.
杰森:你吓了我一跳.
Jason: You startled me.
吉尔:对不起,我只是来透透空气的.
Jill: Sorry, I just came out for a breath of fresh air.
杰森:对,再抽支烟.
Jason: Yeah, and a smoke.
吉尔:那我走.
Jill: I'll leave.
杰森:不不不,继续抽,
Jason: No, no, no you stay, stay and smoke your brains out.
把你的灵魂也抽了,如果活够了,就这样自杀吧.
Go ahead, kill yourself if you want to.
吉尔:你说自杀?
Jill: Kill myself?
杰森:是这样的,我很感谢你没在屋里抽烟.
Jason: Yeah, I do appreciate you not doing it in the house, at least.
吉尔:我如果在这抽烟你也介意.
Jill: Oh, but you don't mind if I off myself out here?
杰森:当然介意,
Jason: No, of course I do,
但我肯定不会强求别人按我的意思行事,
but I certainly can't get people to act the way I'd like them to.
否则今天的情况就两样了.
Otherwise today would have been a lot different.
吉尔:那么我看你干脆就让我在这自杀算了吧.
Jill: So, please excuse me while I finish killing myself.
杰森:我们不再谈论吸烟的事了,行吗?
Jason: We're not talking about smoking anymore, are we?
吉尔:随你.
Jill: No.
杰森:我们不再谈论吸烟的事了,行吗?
Jason: We're not talking about smoking anymore, are we?
吉尔:随你.
Jill: No.
杰森:这确实使我大吃一惊,
Jason's voiceover: I felt as if my breath had been knocked out of me.
突然间我那微不足道的关心和怜悯,
And and with it, all my petty concerns and self-pity.
似乎无济于事,眼前这个充满悲哀的邋遢姑娘,
In that instant, all that mattered was this sad-eyed,
正在拼命地挣扎.
scruffy girl who was trying to be so tough.
杰森:我说的对不对?你打算?
Jason: Do I understand you, are you considering...
吉尔:算了吧!
Jill: Forget it.
杰森:别走啊.
Jason: Now hold on.
吉尔:怎么了,你是不是想彻底改变一下我的人生?
Jill: Why, are you gonna say something that's gonna turn my whole life around?
杰森:不,但我也不会看着你越走越远.
Jason: Well no, but I'm not gonna let you walk away either.
吉尔:听着,没那么严重,知道吗?是跟你开个玩笑.你怎么了?
Jill: Look, I wasn't serious, okay?It was a joke.What's your problem?
杰森:你不能到处流浪.
Jason: Hey, you're not going anywhere.
吉尔:恩?
Jill: Oh yeah?
杰森:等一下.如果你要对我说,
Jason: Just a second, wait a minute.
你对自杀无所谓,
Believe me, if you think you can tell me you're thinking of killing yourself
那你就走吧,但你错了.
then just leave here, you're mistaken.
杰森:现在我们两个态度都很强硬,
Jason's voiceover: Now both of us were acting tough.
但愿我不比她更差.
I only hoped my act was as good as hers.
吉尔:好,耽误你时间了,我们在一起挨冻吧.
Jill: Fine.Waste your time.I'll just stay out here and freeze.
杰森:去我的办公室吧.
Jason: Well why don't we go in my office.
吉尔:不.
Jill: No!
杰森:那好吧,这样也行.
Jason: Okay, fine.This is good.
吉尔:我没什么好谈的.
Jill: I got nothin' to talk about.
杰森:真的?
Jason: Really.
吉尔:对,是真的.
Jill: Yeah.Really.
杰森:我知道你是第一次来这儿,
Jason: Look, I know you came in here tonight for the first time ever.
我也知道你来这儿是为了帮助迈克和波纳的,
I know you're supposed to be here helping Mike and Boner.
我发现你一直在观察着我,你也知道我是个心理专家.
I also know you spend most of your time staring at me.
你想对我说些什么?
I know you know I'm a psychiatrist.So what do you wanna say to me?
吉尔:本来想跟你谈谈的,可现在改主意了,
Jill: Big deal.I just wanted to talk to you, and I changed my mind.
难道不可以吗?
Isn't that allowed?
杰森:可以,可以.
Jason: No!No..
吉尔:我想我说什么呢?这是.
Jill: Look, it's it's... I don't know what to say.It, it, this is just...
杰森:好了好了,这是,你是想告诉我,为什么来找我谈.
Jason: Alright, alright, alright, just uh, tell me why you picked me to talk to.
吉尔:是因为我,我实在没什么人可找了.
Jill: Well it's not like I got a whole lotta people to choose from.
杰森:那么你的父母呢?
Jason: Well uh, what about your parents?
吉尔:我不想.
Jill: Right.
杰森:为什么?你母亲呢?
Jason: Why not?Your mom?
吉尔:她,她不在我身边.
Jill: She's she's not around.
杰森:你父亲呢?
Jason: What about your dad?
吉尔:他太忙.
Jill: Too busy.
杰森:你的朋友呢?
Jason: You got friends?
吉尔:我的朋友少得可怜,
Jill: I only know a couple a people,
也许他们认为自杀是个好主意.
and they'd probably think killing myself was a good idea.
杰森:你的老师呢?
Jason: What about teachers?
吉尔:对,我找哪个呢?
Jill: Oh yeah, which one will it be?Mr.Gardner in Health, or Ms.
卫生课的加娜呢?还是教打字的罗马诺.
Ramano in Typing?
杰森:那么你的这个.
Jason: Okay, how about
吉尔:我都跟你说过了,我没有朋友,但愿我能有.
Jill: Look, it's like I said...there's nobody.I wish there was.
杰森:好,你刚才说你爸爸很忙,可他又不是个的坏人.
Jason: Okay, you said your dad's too busy, uh is he such a bad guy
though?Is
吉尔:指望不了他.
Jill: He couldn't handle it.
杰森:你就这么肯定吗?你要知道做父母的,
Jason: Well are you so sure about that,
他们.
you know sometimes fathers and mothers, they...
吉尔:我母亲自杀,你知道吗?
Jill: My mother killed herself, okay?It was a week before my twelfth birthday.
事情发生在我12岁生日的前几天,说好要参加舞会的.
We were gonna have a party.
杰森:太糟了.
Jason: My god.
吉尔:我没事.这种事我爸爸经历得太多了,
Jill: I'm fine so I'm not about to tell my dad about this,
我不想对他提这事.
after what he's been through.
杰森:这件事太可怕了.
Jason: Well that's a terrible thing for any...
吉尔:没事,我过去常这样.
Jill: I used to feel that way.
杰森:常这样?
Jason: Used to?
吉尔:对.
Jill: Yeah.
杰森:现在你感觉如何?
Jason: What do you feel now?
吉尔:我好像不存在了.
Jill: Like I don't exist.
我好像一直在一个人的梦里徘徊,
Like I'm just walking around in somebody else's dream.
而这个人随时随刻都会醒来.
Any second that person could just wake up and...
杰森:而你也就消失了?
Jason: You'd just disappear, huh?
吉尔:是的.可是有谁会梦见我呢?
Jill: Yeah.And they wouldn't even remember they dreamed me.
听着,你不必为我担忧,
Look, you really shouldn't even bother with me,
我是说我不可能付给你钱,或者其他报酬的.
because I mean it's not like I can afford to pay you or anything, so...
杰森:我好像并没向你要过钱.
Jason: I don't remime it.I didn't ask you for any money.
吉尔:我觉得这是个馊主意,
Jill: Well this whole thing is just a bad idea.
我可以要回我的车钥匙吗?
Can I please have my keys back?
波纳:救命,救命.
Boner: Uh...Help me, help me.
吉尔:天哪.
Jill: God.
杰森:别站着,快进去.
Jason: Hey don't, just stay there Jill.
波纳:Mike,你把我封起来,知道这个怎么脱吗?
Boner: Mikey, why would you put this on me if you didn't know how to get it off?
波纳:Mike,你把我封起来,知道这个怎么脱么?
迈克:只要你把胸脯缩一下,唰,就出去了.
Mike: Boner, it would have been a lot easier if you'd have just shaved your chest.
波纳:西维尔医生,看看我,救救我.
Boner: Dr.Seaver.Look at me.Help me.
迈克:就在那儿,他有把锯子.
Mike: Where is Jill?She's got the saw.
波纳:锯子.
Boner: Saw?
迈克:爸爸你看见了?
Mike: Dad, have you seen her?
杰森:没有.
Jason: No.
波纳:谢谢西维尔医生.
Boner: Oh, thank you, thank you!
迈克:这就怪了,我到处在找它,
Mike: That's weird, I mean I haven't been able to find her anywhere.
它应该在.
She's gotta be out here.
杰森:她不在,迈克.
Jason: Well she isn't, Mike.
迈克:爸爸,你.
Mike: But dad, she...
杰森:迈克,迈克,它不在这儿,懂吗?快把波纳带进去,放在热水里泡一泡.
Jason: Mike, Mike, will you, she's not out here, okay.Will you just take Boner inside and, and soak him in hot water.
迈克:好吧,好吧.
Mike: Okay, okay
波纳:谢谢西维尔大夫,是你救了我.
Boner: Thanks Dr.Seaver, you saved my life.
杰森:吉尔!吉尔
Jason: Jill, Jill?
吉尔:在这儿.谢谢你,没说出我.
Jill: I'm here.Thanks for not saying anything.
杰森:去我的办公室,是不会有干扰的.
Jason: Look, there'd be no interruptions in my office.
吉尔:不.
Jill: No!
杰森:好,就这样.在这儿我们都会被冻死的,我说的是实话.
Jason: Okay, okay, fine.Fine, we'll stay out here and freeze to death.Let me
rephrase that
吉尔:好吧,
Jill: Okay, you wanted to know why I picked you to talk to I'll tell you.
你想知道我为什么找你谈,告诉你是因为Mike,
It's Mike.I had to meet his dad.
我想见见他爸爸,
You know, every time I get sent to Dewitt, the Principal,
每当我被送去见维特校长时,迈克总在那儿.
Mike's usually there.I mean he's the only kid I know who ever gets into
他是唯一像我一样惹事生非的孩子,
as much trouble as me.But, he never seems to get down about it.
可他对这些从来不以为然,即使维特对他吹胡子瞪眼睛,
Even when Dewitt yells at him, he's got this look on his face,
他也能若有其事的瞧着他.
like he's having a good time.
杰森:是的.
Jason: Yeah.
吉尔:就像今天,我们面前是一群社会渣滓,
Jill: Like today, we had to go to this career day garbage,
迈克却拿了一个空盒,
and Mike takes out one of these booths and puts up a sign Sex Therapy:
上面写着性治疗,大夫在里面.
The Doctor is In.
杰森:那才是我的儿子.
Jason: That's my boy.
吉尔:可是维特关了他一个星期的禁闭,我告诉他,
Jill: So Dewitt sent him to detention for the whole week,
我对他的遭遇非常同情,
and I went up to him and I said, you know, hey,
可是你知道他说什么?
I'm sorry you got busted and, and you know what he said:
如果这样能帮助一个可怜的姑娘,倒是值得的.
If I helped just one poor girl out there, it was worth it.
杰森:我非常希望你和迈克都能遵守学校的规章制度,
Jason: But what you have to understand about Mike is that with him,
应该这样.
most of the time that's just his act.I hope.
吉尔:是啊,可是学校里的其他人还没等到毕业,
Jill: Yeah, but everybody else at that school is always running around
就急急忙忙的寻找一条出路,
like they can't wait to graduate and begin life,
就好像要发生激动人心的大事一样?
like great exciting things are gonna happen,
实际上呢,没事.
and the truth is there's really nothing.
杰森:事实不是这样.
Jason: Well that's not true.
吉尔:如果按你说的,那我的未来呢?
Jill: For me it is.What's in my future, huh?Some stupid job.
某个下贱的工作,也许有个残缺的婚姻,
Maybe a lame marriage.
要是我运气还可以的话,我还会有个孩子,遭遇和我一样,
Oh, and then if I'm really lucky,
不,谢谢.
I'll end up with a kid who's just as messed up as me.No thank you.
杰森:事情不一定会这么糟.
Jason: Well it doesn't have to be that way.
吉尔:那么你说吧,没关系的.
Jill: Oh right.Tell my... Never mind.
杰森:你会说告诉我母亲吧.
Jason: You were gonna say tell my mother that,hmm?
吉尔:是的.
Jill: Yeah!
杰森:因为你的母亲对生活失去了信心.
Jason: Cuz your mom, she knew how hopeless life could be.
吉尔:是的.
Jill: Yes!
杰森:你还认为她对.
Jason: And you think she's right.
吉尔:是这样的.
Jill: She was!
杰森:但如果她错了呢?你也认为.
Jason: Mm hmm but what if she was wrong?What if she was?
吉尔:她没错.
Jill: She wasn't!
杰森:如果她为生活不是那么失望呢?
Jason: What if life isn't as empty and hopeless as...
吉尔:要是这样,那就说明我母亲根本不爱我,
Jill: Well then my mom was selfish and she didn't love me at all,
那我也会因为她撇下我和爸爸痛恨她.
and I hate her for what she did to me and my dad.
杰森:看来你对母亲很生气.
Jason: Pretty angry at your mom, aren't you?
吉尔:不.
Jill: No.
杰森:是的,是的,
Jason: Oh yes, yes it's very difficult to be angry at someone close to you,
要对某个亲近的人生气是很困难的,因为你爱她,有时人们做的事情,
someone you love, it, people sometimes do things to,
常常会伤害他们自己,这是因为,因为面子的原因,
they do things to hurt themselves just because, oh,
而不愿意,不愿意承认发过火.
it's so tough they just want to avoid admitting that they're angry.
吉尔:难道你真的认为我会这样,宁愿自杀也不愿意承认,
Jill: Oh, you think that I would really rather kill myself,
我的妈妈她恨我.
then admit that mom that my mom hated me.
杰森:我并没有说你母亲恨你.
Jason: I didn't say your mom hated you.
吉尔:那她为什么一定要自杀?
Jill: Well why else would she kill herself?
杰森:或许她以为她母亲在恨她,或者她有先天障碍,
Jason: Well maybe she thought her mother hated her.
就跟你绝对没有关系,
Maybe she had mental problems that had absolutely nothing to do with you.
或许她是误解了什么,就像你现在这样.
Maybe she was just as confused as you are right now.
吉尔:我认为这纯粹是胡说八道.
Jill: That's the biggest crock I've ever heard.
杰森:她没有立刻接受我的理论,
Jason's voiceover: She didn't immediately embrace my theory,
但我让她说出来了,
but I had her talking,
在她眼神中还有一线新的希望和生气,她开始意识到自己毕竟还是个人,
there was a spark and a vitality in her eyes that was new.
而不是别人梦中的影子,
She was beginning to realize that she was a real person after all and
梦者已经醒来,
not a character in someone's dream.
而她还没有消失.
The dreamer had awakened and she hadn't disappeared.
卡尔:喔.
Carl: Wow.
杰森:好了,时间到了.
Jason: Well, time's up.
卡尔:嘿嘿嘿,你原先并没有讲定时间,
Carl: Hey, hey, hey, hey, you don't get to say when time is up.
现在我是医生,时间该由我来定.
I'm the doctor this time, I get to say when time is up.
杰森:可呼叫器是我的.
Jason: It's my office and my buzzer.
卡尔:可我想知道以后怎么样了.
Carl: Yeah, I wanna know what's happened since then.
杰森:我感到性命攸关,但我能掌握.
Jason: Well I feel vital.I feel competent.
卡尔:你是在说他?
Carl: Not you, her!
杰森:知道知道.
Jason: I know, I know.
卡尔:知道什么?
Carl: How is she?
杰森:知道他会.
Jason: Well, she's um...
卡尔:杰森,我很羡慕你.
Carl: Jason.I envy you.
杰森:我们下周来处理这问题.记住,
Jason: Yeah, well we'll deal with that problem next week.
我两点钟等你.
Right now, I have a two o'clock, c'mon.
卡尔:好吧.
Carl: Okay.
杰森:下周见,卡尔.
Jason: See you next week, Carl.
卡尔:是的,下周轮到你先开始,
Carl: Oh yeah, Only next week you go first,
如果时间不够,那就用我的时间补上.
that way if we run out of time we can take it out of my session.
杰森:你以为这样做好吗?
Jason: Oh, you think that's wise?
卡尔:
Carl: [gasps in mock horror]
杰森:穿上衣服好吗?波纳.
Jason: Oh, put some clothes on, will you, Boner.
杰森:嗨.
Jason: Hi.
吉尔:嗨,周围有人吗?
Jill: Hi.Is anybody else around?
杰森:没有,只有我,
Jason: No, just us.We're ready.Come on in, have a seat.
都准备好了,你就请坐吧,我们还是继续上次的谈话吧.
We'll just, uh, pick up where we left off last time.
吉尔:我想告诉你,
Jill: I wanted to tell you that, I did what you said,
我照你的办法跟我爸爸谈了.
and I uh talked to my dad.
杰森:结果呢?
Jason: And?
吉尔:他拥抱我了,他要参加我的下次咨询.
Jill: He hugged me.He wants to come to my next session.
杰森:真是太好了,下次可以去我的办公室了,
Jason: Well that's wonderful.And maybe we can do it in my office next time.
用不着再到这儿来找椅子了.
Either that, or I'll just pull up another lawn chair here.
吉尔:至少这周已经不同了,在学校里有一个姑娘.
Jill: Anyway, um, this week's been a little different.
她…
There was this girl at school, and um...
杰森:不介意嚼口香糖把?
吉尔:她要借那本书,我说行.于是我们就开始了谈话,然后到她家一起做功课.
00:23:15,200
Jason: Can I have a piece of gum? Jill: She asked to borrow this book and I said okay and we talked a little bit and ended up going over to her house to study...